PROFILE

I am a self-driven experienced UX Designer creating meaningful products and experiences for companies big and small with five years of experience creating exceptional products for businesses of all sizes. I transform brands through a holistic design process combining an understanding of User Experience with Human-Computer Interaction (HCI), Information Architecture, and Interaction Design. What sets me apart is my robust, user-centered design approach. My design process always begins with a deep understanding of the challenge. I allow the user experience to drive this process resulting in beautiful, functional, intuitive, and digitally feasible products

WORK EXPERIENCE

UI / UX Designer (Present)

Medfuture Medical Recruitment | 2021 | Colombo, SL

- Worked with product owners and development teams to define and implement innovative solutions for the product direction, visuals, and experience using wireframes, storyboards, user flows, process flows, and site map
- Experienced with user needs and business requirements as inputs to design and facilitate user empathy mapping principles for crossfunctional teams.
- Experienced with Rapidly iterating on design prototypes and working applications executing all visual design stages from concept to wireframe, and UI handoff for development
- Ability to design support during development and execution to ensure designs are implemented accurately and with the highest standards
- Experienced with building professional, dynamic, and detail-oriented design systems for products

UX Designer

Magellan Champlain | 2019 - 2021 | Colombo, SL

- Conceptualized and executed the creative ideas and next generation of branding to life across all web projects by industry standards and trends
- Hands-on experience in designing information architecture for mobile apps and responsive websites
- Worked closely with developers to make updates on the different iterations of the projects
- Experienced in the design of user interfaces for mobile applications and websites using Sketch
- Worked with bootstrap grid for creating responsive websites

UI Designer (Internship)

Courage in Action | 2018 - 2019 | Toronto, CA

- Designed wireframes, sitemap, and other prototype deliverables with the use of Invision App
- Created design Library elements icon sets button styles for UI elements to be used in the application
- Created clickable and annotated wireframes for every screen and stage of the application with a lot of grids and designed the solutions for multiple tables on the screens for the best user experience that met stakeholder approval
- Worked on the UI of a web-based content management system built with React and Redux

Web Designer

Sapphire Capital Group | 2017 - 2018 | Colombo, SL

- Collaborated work with business team and product owners to comprehend business requirements
- Worked in creating wireframes, mockup and prototype for the mobile application using Sketch
- Contributed to building a user experience pattern library, to maintain consistency in behaviors across multiple products
- Designed Responsive Web layouts for Desktop, Tablet, and Mobile devices using a Responsive Grid design system
- Created React components, using Redux for unidirectional data flow

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

2016 - 2020

Sri Lanka Institute Of Technology

BSc (Hons) in Information Technology Specializing in Interactive Media

KEY SKILLS

- UX Design
- User Interface Design
- Prototype Design
- User Need Analysis
- Personas

- · Competitive Analysis
- A/B Testing
- User Research
- · Usability Testing
- User-Centered Design

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Figma
- · Adobe XD
- Sketch
- Marvel
- Justinmind
- Balsamiq
- Axure

- InVision
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- · Adobe InDesign
- HTML5
- CSS3
- Java Script